Finding Aid for League of Women Voters of Michigan Records 1926-1995
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
League of Women Voters of Michigan Records 1926-1995
League of Women Voters of Michigan.
38 linear feet
Minutes, annual reports, presidents' letters, legislative programs, issue files concerning its involvement with such issues as child welfare, civil service, the Constitutional Convention of 1961-1962, election law reform, environmental quality, fair employment practices, human resources, reapportionment, taxation, and voters services; also include records of local branches.
851728 Bm 2
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The record group was donated by the state office of the LWV (donor no. 4164 ) in 1964. Periodic additions have been made.
The record group is open for research.
The national organization of the League of Women Voters was founded in Chicago in 1920 at the Victory Convention of the National Women's Suffrage Association. Many women felt this last organization should be dissolved when the Nineteenth Amendment became law. Carrie Chapman Catt, however, was determined to create "a living memorial dedicated to the memory of our departed leaders and the sacrifices they made for our cause." This new organization was to assist women in making the decisions which would make their nation safer for their children and their children's children.
Carrie Chapman Catt, Maud Wood Park, Belle Sherman, Marguerite Wells and others set out to create a closely knit organization which would function on national, state, and local levels. Because they realized that the country didn't need more voters, but better informed voters--both men and women--the League of Women Voters established citizenship training programs. They also began to press for governmental reforms.
The League of Women Voters was and is a non-partisan organization, taking stands on issues, rather than individuals, supporting principles, but never particular candidates.
The Michigan League of Women Voters was formed in the early 1920s. The records of the Michigan League of Women Voters cover the period from the 1940s to the 1990s. The issues series document such concerns as environmental quality (air pollution, pesticides, solid waste, and water) as well as human resources (teacher accountability, busing, the Equal Rights Amendment, housing, and social services). There are also large portions of material on taxation, reapportionment, international relations, election law reform, and on the Michigan Constitutional Convention of 1961-1962.
Each local chapter of the LWV was required to send its annual reports to the state league. These reports summarized special programs, membership, and financial information. These, as well as correspondence, by-laws, and in some cases, minutes, bulletins, special reports, and voters guides reflect the concerns and issues which confronted the league on the local level.
In many cases local leagues were disbanded because of lack of interest or because the members joined with other local leagues. These discontinued leagues have been designated by the word defunct after their name. Individuals interested in the Farmington leagues should also consult the material under the heading of West Bloomfield - Farmington. Huntington Woods and Lathrup Village joined the league of Ferndale and Pleasant Ridge. For those interested in the League of Women Voters in the Upper Peninsula consult the local league series under each community as well as the heading of Copper Country.
Subjects:
Allen Park (Mich.); Apportionment (Election law)--Michigan.; Bay City (Mich.); Bay County (Mich.); Birmingham (Mich.); Child welfare--Michigan.; Civil service.; Dearborn (Mich.); Delta County (Mich.); Detroit (Mich.); Discrimination in employment--Michigan.; Elections--Michigan.; Environmental protection--Michigan.; Escanaba (Mich.); Ferndale (Mich.); Flint (Mich.); Genesee County (Mich.); Labor supply--Michigan.; Michigan. Constitutional Convention (1961-1962); Oakland County (Mich.); Taxation--Michigan.; Wayne County (Mich.); Women--Michigan--Societies and clubs.; League of Women Voters of Michigan.
- Background
  - History 1943-1957 (Box 1)
  - By-laws 1926-1971 (Box 1)
  - State officers and directors 1949-1973 (Box 1)
  - Annual reports of state league 1945-1974, 19 folders (Box 1)
- State conventions and conferences
  - Sites and committees 1951-1978 (Box 1)
  - Instructions 1949-1951 (Box 1)
  - Papers 1940-1957, 16 folders (Box 1)
  - Papers 1958-1979, 23 folders (Box 2)
- State board minutes
  - 1940-1952, 10 folders (Box 2)
  - 1953-1974, 32 folders (Box 3)
  - 1975-1983, 9 folders (Box 36)
  - Board Minutes and Reports 1976-1978, 1 volumes (Box 36)
  - Board Minutes and related 1982-1988, 3 folders (Box 36)
- Miscellaneous records
  - Fiftieth Anniversary celebration 1968-1970, 6 folders (Box 36)
  - Presidents' Conference 1950 (Box 36)
  - Reports concerning individual liberties and legislation on subversive activities 1953-1955 (Box 36)
  - Presidents' letter to branches/state board reports 1946-1967, 18 folders (Box 3)
  - Presidents' letter to branches/state board reports 1968-1973, 6 folders (Box 4)
  - Calendar of events 1968-1973 (Box 4)
  - General program of activities 1958-1970, 8 folders (Box 4)
  - Workshops 1967-1972, 6 folders (Box 4)
  - Financial records
    - General 1949-1961, 8 folders (Box 4)
    - Financial statements 1962-1990, 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Metro finance committee correspondence and memoranda 1957-1966 (Box 4)
    - Finance/Development 1971-1975 (Box 4)
  - "Know Your State" booklet
    - General 1953-1956, 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Resource material 1951-1957, 5 folders (Box 4)
    - Promotional material 1957-1958 (Box 4)
  - Legislative programs
    - State programs 1961-1969 (Box 4)
    - Legislative day 1956-1958 (Box 4)
    - Call for Action 1963-1966, 3 folders (Box 4)
    - House bills 1945-1953, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Membership 1970-1977 (Box 5)
- Issues
  - Campaign finance reform 1973-1974 (Box 5)
  - Children's service
    - General undated, 1941-1949, 8 folders (Box 5)
    - Correspondence, Reports and Pamphlets 1949-1956, 15 folders (Box 5)
  - Civil service
    - General 1936-1946, 3 folders (Box 5)
    - Correspondence 1947 (Box 5)
    - Statistics 1947 (Box 5)
    - Papers 1948-1957 (Box 5)
  - Constitutional amendment-Judicial selection and tenure 1967-1968, 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Constitutional convention
    - Undated 1946-1955, 7 folders (Box 5)
    - 1956
      - Correspondence (Box 6)
      - Reports and clippings (Box 6)
    - 1957
      - Correspondence (Box 6)
      - Minutes (Box 6)
      - Pamphlets (Box 6)
      - Supporter list (Box 6)
      - Newspaper clippings and press releases (Box 6)
      - Miscellanea (Box 6)
    - 1958
      - Correspondence, 2 folders (Box 6)
      - Statements (Box 6)
      - Minutes of Citizens' Committee on state constitutional convention (Box 6)
      - Program activities and flyers (Box 6)
      - Financial information (Box 6)
      - Supporters list (Box 6)
      - Party county chairpersons (Box 6)
      - Suggestions for successful Constitutional Convention (Box 6)
      - Speakers bureau (Box 6)
      - Michigan Constitutional Convention kit (Box 6)
      - Skits (Box 6)
      - Newspaper clippings and press releases (Box 6)
      - Memorabilia (Box 6)
      - Miscellanea (Box 6)
    - 1959 Miscellaneous (Box 6)
    - 1960
      - Correspondence (Box 6)
      - Statements (Box 6)
      - Skits (Box 6)
      - Press releases (Box 6)
      - Miscellanea 1960 (Box 6)
    - High school mock Constitutional Convention
      - Correspondence 1957 (Box 6)
      - Organization 1957 (Box 6)
      - Miscellanea 1957 (Box 6)
      - Correspondence 1958 (Box 6)
      - Program 1958 (Box 6)
      - Reports 1958 (Box 6)
      - Newspaper clippings 1953 (Box 6)
      - Miscellanea 1958 (Box 6)
      - Papers 1959 (Box 6)
    - 1961 (Box 6)
  - County home rule 1960-1968, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Courts 1967-1974, 3 folders (Box 6)
  - Education 1969-1974, 3 folders (Box 6)
  - Election law reform 1951-1958, 7 folders (Box 7)
  - Electoral College 1968-1972 (Box 7)
  - Environmental quality
    - Air 1970-1974 (Box 7)
    - Air pollution 1972-1973 (Box 7)
    - Pesticides 1969-1972 (Box 7)
    - Solid waste 1971-1974 (Box 7)
    - Water and related issues
      - General 1966-1975 (Box 7)
      - Holding tanks 1970-1971 (Box 7)
      - Inland lakes and streams (Box 7)
      - Lake Erie Basin Committee 1963-1974 (Box 7)
      - Lake Michigan Inter-League Group
        - Correspondence 1967-1974 (Box 7)
        - Reports 1968-1974 (Box 7)
        - Newsletters 1968-1974 (Box 7)
        - Bulletins 1973-1974 (Box 7)
        - Minutes, reports, statements 1971-1978, 4 folders (Box 7)
        - Miscellaneous studies (Box 7)
      - Saginaw River basin group 1970-1971 (Box 8)
      - Shorelands 1972-1974 (Box 8)
      - Miscellaneous studies and reports (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous papers 1946-1979, 13 folders (Box 8)
  - Ethics-Political 1973 (Box 8)
  - Fair Employment Practices Commission
    - Undated (Box 8)
    - 1943-1944 (Box 8)
    - Correspondence 1945-1946 (Box 8)
    - Newsletters 1945-1946 (Box 8)
    - Reports 1945-1946 (Box 8)
    - 1947 (Box 8)
    - 1948-1949 (Box 8)
    - 1950-1951 (Box 8)
    - Correspondence 1952 (Box 8)
    - Reports and bills 1952 (Box 8)
    - Correspondence 1953 (Box 8)
    - Reports and testimony 1953 (Box 8)
    - Clippings 1953 (Box 8)
    - 1954 (Box 8)
    - 1955 (Box 8)
    - 1956-1959 (Box 8)
  - Green grass roots 1969-1974 (Box 8)
  - Human resources
    - Accountability
      - Correspondence 1969-1974 (Box 8)
      - Reports and testimony 1969-1974 (Box 8)
    - Busing
      - Correspondence 1971-1974 (Box 8)
      - Reports 1971-1973 (Box 8)
    - Children's services
      - Correspondence 1971-1974 (Box 8)
      - Reports and testimony 1967-1974 (Box 8)
    - Civil rights 1972-1974 (Box 8)
    - Education 1968-1969 (Box 8)
    - Equal rights amendment
      - Correspondence 1973-1975 (Box 8)
      - Reports and testimony 1974 (Box 8)
    - Housing
      - Correspondence 1969-1974 (Box 9)
      - Reports and testimony 1968-1974 (Box 9)
    - School desegregation 1972-1973 (Box 9)
    - Social services
      - Correspondence 1971-1974 (Box 9)
      - Reports and testimony 1971-1974 (Box 9)
    - Miscellanea 1971-1974, 2 folders (Box 9)
    - National program
      - Education 1969-1973 (Box 9)
      - Environmental quality 1970 (Box 9)
      - Housing 1968-1974 (Box 9)
      - Newsletters 1974 (Box 9)
      - Integration 1968-1970 (Box 9)
      - Revenue sharing 1969-1974 (Box 9)
      - Welfare 1969-1970 (Box 9)
      - Committee Guide, 1970-1971 (Box 9)
      - Current Focus, 1970 (Box 9)
      - Facts and Issues, 1971 (Box 9)
      - Human Resources Newsletter, 1969 (Box 9)
      - Miscellanea 1967-1974 (Box 9)
  - International relations 1963-1975, 5 folders (Box 9)
  - Land use 1971-1974 (Box 9)
  - Legislation
    - Action program 1970-1974 (Box 9)
    - Action information dispatch 1974-1975 (Box 9)
    - Procedures for interviewing representatives 1973-1974 (Box 9)
    - Fact sheets 1973-1974 (Box 9)
    - Michigan legislative seminar 1973-1974 (Box 9)
    - Miscellanea 1973-1974 (Box 9)
  - Local government 1963-1974, 3 folders (Box 10)
  - Open meetings Act 1974 (Box 10)
  - Petition drive 1970 (Box 10)
  - Public relations 1950-1967, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Public welfare 1963-1972, 5 folders (Box 10)
  - Reapportionment
    - General undated (Box 10)
    - General 1949, 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Minutes 1950 (Box 10)
    - Speeches 1950 (Box 10)
    - Resolutions 1950 (Box 10)
    - Miscellanea 1950 (Box 10)
    - General 1951 (Box 10)
    - Correspondence 1952 (Box 10)
    - Resolutions 1952 (Box 10)
    - Positions 1952 (Box 10)
    - Press releases and newspaper clippings 1952 (Box 10)
    - Miscellanea 1952 (Box 10)
    - General 1953 (Box 10)
    - General 1964-1972 (Box 10)
  - Representative government 1969-1975 (Box 10)
  - Revenue sharing
    - Correspondence 1974-1975 (Box 10)
    - Press releases and newspaper clippings 1974 (Box 10)
    - Miscellanea 1972-1974 (Box 10)
  - Social services
    - Correspondence 1971-1972 (Box 10)
    - Miscellanea 1971-1974 (Box 10)
  - Taxation
    - General undated (Box 11)
    - General 1939-1944 (Box 11)
    - General 1945 (Box 11)
    - General 1946 (Box 11)
    - General 1947 (Box 11)
    - General 1948 (Box 11)
    - Correspondence 1949 (Box 11)
    - Reports 1949, 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Correspondence 1950 (Box 11)
    - Reports 1950 (Box 11)
    - Pamphlets 1950 (Box 11)
    - Correspondence 1951 (Box 11)
    - Reports 1951 (Box 11)
    - Correspondence 1952 (Box 11)
    - Reports 1952 (Box 11)
    - Newspaper clippings 1952 (Box 11)
    - Correspondence 1953 (Box 11)
    - Reports 1953 (Box 11)
    - Correspondence 1954 (Box 11)
    - Reports 1954 (Box 11)
    - Publications 1954 (Box 11)
    - General 1955-1958 (Box 11)
    - General 1959-1961 (Box 11)
    - General 1962-1964 (Box 11)
    - General 1965-1970 (Box 11)
    - General 1971 (Box 11)
    - General 1972-1974 (Box 11)
  - Trade 1970-1974 (Box 11)
  - United Nations 1963-1975 (Box 11)
  - U.S. Congress 1970-1972 (Box 11)
  - Voters service
    - Correspondence 1964-1974, 3 folders (Box 12)
    - Policies 1962 (Box 12)
    - Political organization and conventions 1967-1969 (Box 12)
    - Candidate questionnaires
      - 1968 (Box 12)
      - 1970 (Box 12)
    - Election guidelines
      - 1968-1969 (Box 12)
      - 1970-1973 (Box 12)
    - Workshops
      - 1965-1969 (Box 12)
      - 1973 (Box 12)
    - Instructions 1950-1959 (Box 12)
    - Voters service kit 1960, 1964 (Box 12)
    - ABC election night reporting concerning key precincts 1966-1974 (Box 12)
    - Free Press election night reporting concerning key precincts 1974 (Box 12)
    - Minutes of Wayne County voters service committee 1968 (Box 12)
    - Congressional roll call votes 1956-1964 (Box 12)
    - The Polling Place, 1973-1974 (Box 12)
    - Voters Guide
      - 1956-1963 (Box 12)
      - 1964-1972 (Box 12)
    - Miscellanea 1956-1974, 3 folders (Box 12)
    - National election material 1969-1974, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Voting rights
    - Correspondence 1970-1974 (Box 12)
    - Legislative 1973-1974 (Box 12)
    - Publications 1970-1973 (Box 12)
    - Miscellanea 1972-1974 (Box 12)
    - Courts 1955-1956 (Box 12)
    - Education 1953-1956 (Box 12)
    - Governmental organizations 1950-1952, 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Governor 1955-1956 (Box 12)
    - Home rule 1949-1954, 3 folders (Box 12)
    - Legislature 1950-1955, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Printed material
    - State administration 1950-1955 (Box 13)
    - State aid to schools 1953-1955, 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Finance publications from other states, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Legislative News 1954-1976, 5 folders (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous papers
    - Undated 1939-1975, 26 folders (Box 13)
    - County councils 1947-1953 (Box 13)
    - Information and reports requested from local leagues 1949-1957 (Box 13)
    - Kits to aid in organization undated, 1945-1947 (Box 13)
    - Techniques for organizing units and discussions 1944-1954 (Box 13)
    - Materials used to aid provisional leagues 1947-1953 (Box 13)
- Local leagues
  - Administrative
    - Policies and procedures 1968-1970 (Box 14)
    - Local league presidents 1959-1968 (Box 14)
    - Potential league organization 1951-1967 (Box 14)
    - Local programs 1954-1970 (Box 14)
  - Local chapter records
    - Algonac (defunct)
      - Annual reports 1947-1950 (Box 14)
      - Correspondence 1947-1950 (Box 14)
    - Allen Park
      - By-laws undated, 1953, 1959 (Box 14)
      - Annual reports 1955-1970, 5 folders (Box 14)
      - Correspondence 1952-1976 (Box 14)
      - Minutes 1955-1960, 5 folders (Box 14)
      - Bulletins 1957-1959 (Box 14)
      - Know your town 1956 manuscript (Box 14)
      - Newspaper clippings 1956-1959 (Box 14)
    - Alpena County
      - By-laws undated (Box 14)
      - Annual reports 1964-1975, 3 folders (Box 14)
      - Correspondence 1968-1970 (Box 14)
    - Ann Arbor
      - Annual reports 1951-1970, 4 folders (Box 14)
      - Miscellanea (Box 14)
    - Battle Creek (defunct)
      - Annual reports 1957-1971 (Box 14)
      - Correspondence 1957-1971 (Box 14)
      - Newspaper clippings 1957-1971 (Box 14)
      - Miscellanea (Box 14)
    - Bay City
      - Annual reports
        - 1953 1956-1961 (Box 14)
        - 1970-1974 (Box 14)
      - Minutes 1955-1960, 6 folders (Box 14)
      - Correspondence 1956-1960 (Box 14)
      - Bulletins 1957-1960 (Box 14)
      - Voters guides undated, 1956-1960 (Box 14)
      - Newspaper clippings 1956-1960 (Box 14)
    - Benton Harbor-St. Joseph
      - Annual reports 1963-1970 (Box 14)
      - Correspondence
        - 1957-1958 1962 (Box 14)
        - 1968-1977 (Box 14)
      - Financial information 1971-1974 (Box 14)
      - Recognition applications 1962-1963, 1966 (Box 14)
      - Consultant reports 1961-1972 (Box 14)
      - Fact sheets 1964 (Box 14)
      - Annual meeting workbooks 1963-1965, 1969 (Box 14)
    - Birmingham-Bloomfield
      - By-laws 1957, 1965, 1970, 1972 (Box 15)
      - Annual reports 1948-1974, 6 folders (Box 15)
      - Correspondence 1947-1971, 2 folders (Box 15)
      - Minutes 1956-1960, 5 folders (Box 15)
      - Minutes 1970-1972 (Box 15)
      - Bulletins 1957-1960 (Box 15)
      - Voters guide 1970-1972 (Box 15)
      - Standards and policies undated, 1953 (Box 15)
      - Newspaper clippings 1950-1957 (Box 15)
      - Miscellanea (Box 15)
    - Copper Country
      - By-laws 1956, 1959, 1964 (Box 15)
      - Annual reports 1959-1974, 4 folders (Box 15)
      - Correspondence 1954-1970, 4 folders (Box 15)
        (include file re formation of Ontonagon league, 1966)
      - Minutes 1959 (Box 15)
      - Non-partisan statement 1962-1963 (Box 15)
      - Voters profiles 1970-1971 (Box 15)
      - Miscellanea (Box 15)
    - Dearborn
      - By-laws undated, 1957, 1959, 1965, 1968 (Box 15)
      - Annual reports 1952-1970, 4 folders (Box 15)
      - Correspondence 1951-1967 (Box 15)
      - Minutes 1955-1960, 5 folders (Box 15)
      - Policies and procedures 1961-1965 (Box 15)
        (including non-partisan policy)
      - Bulletins 1957-1960, 4 folders (Box 15)
      - Voters guides 1967-1970 (Box 15)
      - Miscellanea (Box 15)
    - Dearborn Heights
      - By laws 1979 (Box 16)
      - Annual reports 1966-1972, 3 folders (Box 16)
      - Correspondence 1966-1972 (Box 16)
      - Non-partisan policy 1968, 1971 (Box 16)
      - Voters guides 1967, 1970 (Box 16)
      - Miscellanea (Box 16)
    - Delta County
      - Annual reports 1972-1974 (Box 16)
      - Correspondence 1968-1973 (Box 16)
      - Minutes 1972-1974 (Box 16)
    - Detroit
      - By laws 1953, 1957, 1971 (Box 16)
      - Annual reports 1948-1974, 7 folders (Box 16)
      - Correspondence 1949-1977, 3 folders (Box 16)
      - Minutes 1955-1960, 5 folders (Box 16)
      - Bulletins 1957-1960, 2 folders (Box 16)
      - National voters survey 1954 (Box 16)
      - Voters guides undated, 1952, 1959, 1967-1972 (Box 16)
      - Report: Detroit Police Department problems and possibilities 1967 (Box 16)
      - Report on equal justice council 1969 (Box 16)
      - Newspaper clippings 1967-1970 (Box 16)
    - Detroit Metro Area
      - By-laws undated, 1973, 1975 (Box 16)
      - Annual reports 1974 (Box 16)
      - Correspondence 1972-1974 (Box 16)
      - Minutes 1972 (Box 16)
      - Convention 1974 (Box 16)
    - Downriver Wayne County
      - By laws 1962 (Box 16)
      - Annual reports 1961-1974, 3 folders (Box 16)
      - Correspondence 1961-1970 (Box 16)
      - Non-partisan policy statement 1964 (Box 16)
      - Voters service 1971, 1974 (Box 16)
    - Escanaba
      - By-laws undated, 1960, 1962 (Box 16)
      - Annual reports 1952-1971, 6 folders (Box 16)
      - Correspondence 1950-1964 (Box 16)
      - Minutes 1955-1960, 4 folders (Box 16)
      - Bulletins 1957-1960, 4 folders (Box 16)
      - Voters Service report 1958 (Box 16)
      - Newspaper clippings 1955-1958 (Box 16)
    - Farmington
      - By-laws undated (Box 17)
      - Annual reports 1963-1969, 2 folders (Box 17)
      - Non-partisan policy 1965 (Box 17)
      - Minutes 1963, 1968-1969, 2 folders (Box 17)
      - Newspaper clippings undated, 1964 (Box 17)
    - Ferndale-Pleasant Ridge
      - By-laws 1955 (Box 17)
      - Annual reports 1951-1970, 4 folders (Box 17)
      - Correspondence undated, 1951-1958 (Box 17)
      - Minutes 1955-1960, 4 folders (Box 17)
      - Bulletins 1957-1960 (Box 17)
      - Voters service 1951-1954 (Box 17)
      - Newspaper clippings undated, 1959 (Box 17)
      - Miscellanea (Box 17)
    - Flint
      - By-laws undated, 1950, 1955, 1958-1959, 1963 (Box 17)
      - Annual reports 1947-1972, 5 folders (Box 17)
      - Correspondence 1954-1974 (Box 17)
      - Minutes 1955-1960, 6 folders (Box 17)
      - Bulletins. 1957-1960, 4 folders (Box 17)
      - Voters service 1951-1954 (Box 17)
      - League history 1972 (Box 17)
      - Miscellanea (Box 17)
    - Grand Haven
      - By-laws undated (Box 17)
      - Annual reports 1947-1974, 4 folders (Box 17)
      - Correspondence 1948-1976 (Box 17)
      - Voters service 1954 (Box 17)
      - Minutes 1967 (Box 17)
    - Grand Rapids
      - By-laws 1956, 1960 (Box 17)
      - Annual reports 1947-1974, 5 folders (Box 17)
      - Correspondence 1960-1974 (Box 17)
      - Non-partisan Policy 1959 (Box 17)
      - Minutes 1968 (Box 17)
      - Voters service 1951 (Box 17)
      - Miscellanea (Box 17)
    - Grand Traverse area
      - By-laws undated, 1967 (Box 18)
      - Annual reports 1960-1974, 3 folders (Box 18)
      - Correspondence 1951-1973 (Box 18)
      - Non-partisan policy 1962 (Box 18)
      - Libel suit 1964-1965 (Box 18)
      - Miscellanea (Box 18)
    - Gratiot County
      - Annual reports 1964-1975, 4 folders (Box 18)
      - Correspondence 1963-1973 (Box 18)
      - Non-partisan Policy 1970 (Box 18)
      - Voters guide 1970 (Box 18)
    - Grosse Pointe
      - By-laws undated, 1959, 1960, and 1967 (Box 18)
      - Annual reports 1950-1970, 5 folders (Box 18)
      - Correspondence 1964-1977 (Box 18)
      - Non-partisan policy 1961, 1962, 1964, 1967 (Box 18)
      - Voters guides 1952, 1954 (Box 18)
    - Holland
      - By-laws 1969 (Box 18)
      - Annual reports 1969-1974, 2 folders (Box 18)
      - Correspondence 1956-1970 (Box 18)
      - Miscellanea (Box 18)
    - Iron County (defunct)
      - By-laws 1956 (Box 18)
      - Annual reports 1967-1968 (Box 18)
      - Correspondence 1968-1969 (Box 18)
      - Minutes 1966-1968 (Box 18)
      - Membership and leadership lists 1968 (Box 18)
      - Budget 1969 (Box 18)
      - Bulletins 1968 (Box 18)
      - Miscellanea 1967-1969 (Box 18)
    - Iron Mountain (defunct)
      - By-laws undated (Box 18)
      - Annual reports 1950-1954 (Box 18)
      - Correspondence 1949-1955 (Box 18)
      - Membership 1948-1951 (Box 18)
      - Voters service report 1951 (Box 18)
      - Newspaper clippings 1949-1950 (Box 18)
      - Miscellanea (Box 18)
    - Interlake area of Oakland County (defunct)
      - By-laws undated (Box 18)
      - Correspondence undated, 1948-1950 (Box 18)
      - Membership lists undated, 1948-1953 (Box 18)
      - Newspaper clippings undated, 1950 (Box 18)
      - Miscellanea (Box 18)
    - Jackson County
      - By-laws undated, 1957 (Box 18)
      - Annual reports 1947, 1951-1971, 5 folders (Box 18)
      - Correspondence 1951-1969 (Box 18)
      - Voters service report 1954 (Box 18)
      - Miscellanea (Box 18)
    - Jenison (Box 18)
    - Kalamazoo
      - By-laws undated, 1955 (Box 18)
      - Annual reports 1951-1965, 3 folders (Box 18)
      - Annual reports 1966-1976, 3 folders (Box 19)
      - Correspondence 1945-1969 (Box 19)